A Guide to the Papers of Dr. August E. Kehr
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10553-ab
Papers of Dr. August E. Kehr ca. 1924-1994
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10553-ab
ca. 700 items
Dr. August E. Kehr
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by August E. Kehr, Hendersonville, North Carolina, on December 30, 1994.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of August E. Kehr, ca. 1924-1994, ca. 700 items, ca. 2 cu. ft. includes a scrapbook, "4H Clubbing It", 1924-1931, recording Kehr's 4 H activities in Unadilla, New York; a resume of experience and training for Kehr, 1994; a few printed items, including chapter newsletters and articles; and correspondence of Kehr with fellow rhododendron and magnolia enthusiasts, ca. 1967-1994. The number of letters from each correspondent follows their name. For additional August E. Kehr papers and biographical information see the guide for accession number 10553-b.
Alphabetical List of Correspondents
A
1989
Richard Abel
1986-1988
Robert W. Adams (2)
1990
Carl [Amason] (2)
1992
Tomasz Arisko
1986-1990
Kenichi Arisumi (5)
1991
Dr. James R. Ault
B
1987
Bob Badger
1984-1994
Reid Bahnson (7)
1987
Dr. James R. Ballington (3)
1990 & 1993
Boris F. Bauer (2)
1983 & 1993
Walter G. Beasley (3)
1992 & 1994
Norman & Jean Beaudry(2)
1992-1993
Sid Beck (2)
1986
C. Ritchie Bell
1989
Warren Berg
1986
Edmund Berkeley, Jr.
1985
Janet E. Binford
1993-1994
Richard E. Bir (2)
1988-1992, n.d.
Os Blumhardt (individual folder, 7 items)
n.d.
Hugh Bollinger
1986
C.A. Borgman
1988
Henk Borsje
1987
Lynn G. Bowen
1993
Robert E. Bowman, Jr.
1987
C.D. Brickell
1994
Briggs Nurseries (2)
1989-1993, n.d.
Phelan Bright, Magnolia Society Sec./Treas. (individual folder, 7 items)
1982 & 1990
Judson Brooks (2)
1993-1994
Dick Brooks, President ARS re Kehr's Pioneer Achievement Award (3)
1987 & 1994
Paul "Bud" Brown (2)
1993
Barbara Buchanan
1986
Dr. Forrest E. Bump
1987 & 1993
Dr. Max Byrkit (2)
1987 & 1994
Michael E. Byrne (2)
C
1991-1992
Larry Cadman (2)
1991-1994
Dorothy Callaway (individual folder, 10 items)
1987
Bob Carlson
1989-1993
John D. Carlson (individual folder, 12 items)
1987
Paula L. Cash
1991-1994
Ray Carter (5)
1993
P. De Ceuster
1990-1993
J.M. Chapman (3)
1987
Arthur A. Childers
1986-1987
Citizen Ambassador Program (7)
1992
Richard E. Clapp
1988
Cathy L. Cochran
1988
Joe H. Coleman
1987
Richard A. Coleman
n.d.
Sheila Collenette
n.d.
Brent Conley (2)
1993-1994
Jim Corbin (3)
1991
Peter Cox (3)
1991
Michael A. Creel
1988
Dwight R. Crocker, Sr.
1994
Harold L. Crutchen
1987
Fred V. Cummings
1990
Betty Cummins (6)
D
1989
Carol Dancer
1988
Edith Davis
1994
Bijan Dehgan
1987
William R. Dodd
1993
Ruth Anne Drechsel
1987
Dorothy Dunstan
E
1987
S. Christopher Early
1990
Lesley Eaton
1988
Fran Egan (2)
1990
John Eiselein
1985-1994
Otto Eisenhut (6)
1986-1987
Mohamed El-Gammal (2)
1991
Charles B. Evans
F
1987
Christopher Fairweather
1988-1991
Charles & Jan Flick(5)
1986-1991
Karl Flinck (7)
1982
Thomas M. Foglietta
1987-1991
Marion Francisco (4)
1988
Brigitte Fugl
G
n.d.
Amy Gable
1988-1993
Caroline Gable (7)
1986
John Galbo
1991 & 1994
J.T. Gallagher (2)
1990
Fred C. Galle
1986-1994
Dr. Frank B. Galyon (individual folder, 26 items)
1988
German Genealogical Society of America (3)
1986-1994
Russell Gilkey (7)
1988
Jay Y. Gillenwater
n.d.
Barry Glick
1993-1994
Peter Goodfield (2)
1991-1992
Ray & Jane Goodrich(3)
1992
Martin A. Grantham
1980
Jim Greenway
1991
Lance Greve
1990
[Dr. Dick Gustafson ?]
H
1988-1993
Velma & Charles Haag(4)
1994
Roberta Davids Hagen (2)
n.d.
Mark Haines
1989
Barbara R. Hall (2)
1988-1992
Curt Hanson (3)
1986 & 1992
Shirley Harry (2)
1989
M.J. Harvey
1993
Ray Head
1986-1994
Harry Heinemann (individual folder, 19 items)
1994
John Heinze
1986
Delbert D. Hemphill (2)
n.d.
Josephine de N. Henry
1990-1992
Steve Herje (6)
1984-1986
Kitty Heslin (2)
1987
Rich Hesselein (2)
1986
Dr. J. Heursel (2)
1986-1994
Joseph W. Hickman (individual folder, 13 items)
1989-1992
Polly Hill (6)
1984 & 1988
Dr. Shuichi Hirao (2)
1992-1993
Robert J. Hoffman (3)
1979-1980
W.D. Hogan (5)
1994
Lloyd & Helen Hohn
1984-1994
Harold Hopkins (6)
1986
James H. Horton
J
1987-1994
Dick Jaynes (4)
1986-1990
Adele Jones (4)
1986-1989
Joe W. Jones (4)
1985-1994
Lennarth Jonsson (individual folder, 15 items)
1983-1991
Mark Jury (4)
K
1988-1989
Elizabeth Kagin (2)
1989
Mary Kagin
1987-1994
Olav Kalleberg (individual folder, 28 items)
1983-1989
Austin Kennell (8)
1985 & 1991
Don King (2)
1982
T.B. Kinney, Jr.
1987-1992
Roy Klehm (5)
1994
William & Arlene Klippel
1987-1991
Lola E. Koerting (4)
L
1990-1991
Larry W. Langford (3)
1993
Toni Lawson-Hall (2)
1993
Daniel M. Layman
1986-1994
David Leach (5)
1989
Robert Lee
1987
Henry F. Leweling (2)
1993-1994
Barbara Leypoldt (4)
1991 & 1994
Louisiana Nursery (2)
M
1987
Elizabeth McClintock (2)
1987
Gilbert D. McCollum
1986-1988
Sandra McDonald (individual folder, 10 items)
1989
A.D. McNees (2)
1988
Tetsuo Magaki (3)
1985-1986
Charles Egbert Main (2)
1981
Alfred S. Martin
1987
John May
1982-1993
Virginia Melnick (individual folder, 22 items)
1990-1991
Scott A. Merkle (4)
1993
Jef Van Meulder
1987-1994
Fred Meyer (6)
1991
Paul W. Meyer (3)
1982-1993
George & Betty Miller(5)
1987-1988
William C. Miller III
1989
Roy & Barbara Milne
1992
Fred Minch
1994
Irene Morse
1987-1993
Dr. Frank D. Mossman (12)
1994
George W. Muller (1909-1994, obituary)
1991 & 1994
Jan W. Murray (3)
N-O
1991-1994
Perry F. Narten (4)
1992
Durell Nelson
1991-1994
Sonja Nelson, Editor of
Journal of the American Rhododendron Society
(7)
1987-1994
Samuel N. Norris (9)
1988
Dr. Hiroshi Okada
P-Q
1985-1986
John Palmer (4)
1994
Gunter Pardatscher (2)
1991
Gerardo Perlasca
1991
R.D. Plowman
1987
Ward F. Porter
n.d.
Jess V. Quintana
R
1987
Dr. Herbert Racoff
1986
Dorothy M. Rathmann
1989
Mary S. Rawlinson
1990 & 1993
H. Edward Reiley (2)
1994
Bill Rhein (3)
1967, 1986-1993
George Ring (5)
1994
Nollie Robinson, Jr.
1986-1987
Mary Jane Rodgers (2)
1985-1989
Tsuneshige Rokujo (4)
1987
Eric E. Roos
1992-1994
Jack Rosenthal (4)
1991-1992
Henry A. Ross (6)
1987 & 1990
John Rouse (2)
ca. 1986
Howard Ruppender
S
1989 & 1992
Homer Sally (2)
1993
Merle Sanders
1985
Ralph Sangster
1987-1994
Phil Savage (6)
1988-1989
Henry A. Schannen (3)
1985
Edward Schell
1994
Robert L. Schwind (4)
1987-1988
Tilde [Schwourgrnber ?]
1991-1994
Philip Seitner (individual folder, 11 items)
1989
Gordon W. Severe
1986-1991
Terry Sheuchenko (3)
n.d.
Ginny & Lewis Short
1990
Jouett Shouse
1988-1991
June Sinclair (3)
1991 & 1994
Peter Smithers (3)
1986
Dr. Herbert A. Spady
1991-1992
Philippe de Spoelberch (2)
1991
Mike Stamberg
1986
Carl C. Steinman
1988
Wanda Stinchcomb
1987
Art & Eleanor Stubbs(3)
1971 & 1993
Maurice Sumner (1900-1993, death of) (3)
1985
Hideo Suzuki
1989-1993
George Switzer (3)
T
1994
Hazel E. Tarpley, Magnolia Society Treasurer (3)
1989
Marie Taylor (2)
1989
Audrey Teasdale
1987
C.M. Terry
1990
Raymond G. Tessmer, Jr.
1989
Robert L. Ticknor
1986
Y.C. Ting
1991
John D. Tobe (2)
n.d.
James R. Todd, Jr.
1994
Clarence Towe (2)
1986
David Trehane
1994
Neil G. Treseder
V
1986-1994
Dan Veazey (7)
1986-1994
Piet Van Veen (4)
1986
Ted Van Veen
n.d.
Dave Veinotte
1994
Peter H. Velguth
1986-1987
Donald H. Voss (3)
W-Z
1990-1991
Geoffrey Wakefield (4)
1994
Philip Waldman (2)
1990
Clare McVickar Ward
1989 & 1994
W.A. Warid (2)
1986-1994
John Weagle (3)
1992
Gunnar Weimarck
1988
Rick Wells
1990-1994
Dr. Frank H. West (3)
1967 & 1973
Bishop W. Von Wettburg (2)
1987
Thomas W. Whitaker
1994
Mark P. Widrlechner
1992
David Wilde
1988 & n.d.
David J. Williams
1987-1989
Harry Wise (3)
1994
George Woodard (2)
1986-1987
Evelyn Woods (2)
1993
Dana Woody
1988 & 1991
Gordon K. Wylie (2)
1990
Patty [Yeast]
1991
Matt Zack
1983 & 1988
Unidentified
Container List
- Correspondence: A, 1986-1992 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: B, 1982-1994 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: Os Blumhardt, 1988-1992, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: Phelan Bright (Magnolia Society Secretary/Treasurer, 1989-1993, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: C, 1986-1994 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: Dorothy Callaway, 1991-1994 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: John D. Carlson, 1989-1993 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: D-E, 1985-1994 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: F, 1982-1991 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: G, 1980-1994 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: Dr. Frank B. Galyon, 1986-1994 (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence: H, 1979-1994, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: Harry Heineman, 1986-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: Joseph W. Hickman, 1986-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: J, 1983-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: Lennarth Jonsson, 1985-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: K, 1982-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: Olav Kalleberg, 1987-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: L, 1986-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: M, 1982-1994 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence: Sandra McDonald, 1986-1988 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: Virginia Melnick, 1982-1993 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: N, 1987-1994 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: O-P-Q, 1985-1994, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: R, 1967, 1985-1994 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: S, 1971-1994; (2 folders) (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: Philip Seitner, 1991-1994 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: T, 1986-1994, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: V, 1986-1994 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence: W, 1967-1994 (Box Box 4)
- Correspondence: Y-Z, and unidentified, 1983-1991 (Box Box 4)
- Articles, Chapter Newsletters, etc., 1970-1994, n.d. (Box Box 4)
- "4 H Clubbing It 1924-1931" Scrapbook recording the 4 H activities of August E. Kehr, Unadilla, New York (Box Box 4)
- Resume of Experience and Training - August E. Kehr, 1994 (Box Box 4)